Benjamin Franklin Papers Part 14 -- Materials held at the University of Pennsylvania 1705-1788 Mss.B.F85inventory14
American Philosophical Society
- Correspondence (University of Pennsylvania), 1758-1788
  - to William Temple Franklin, Passy., L.S. 1p.; Pechigny, Madame Devillier
    Terms upon which his protégé may be received into the writer's school.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1784 August 2; 1p.; Hoffman, -----
    Page with ornamental heading, showing the new art of polytype invented by M. Hoffman.
  - to Benjamin [Franklin] Bache., 1784 October 14 and 1785 July 2; Mem. 1p.; -----, -----
    Tailor's bill.
    (Latter part torn off.)
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1787; Mem. 1p.; -----, -----
    List of boys in his Excellency's, Dr. Franklin's, Charity School.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1788 July 4; 1p.; -----, -----
    Ode in honor of the day. Printed broadside.
  - Appendix, L. 3p.; -----, -----
    Project for the formation of two picked companies under the title, "Volunteers of Franklin."
    (In French. In duplicate.)
  - Appendix, Diss. 4p.; -----, -----
    An essay on the evils of paper currency.
  - Appendix, Dis. 16p.; -----, -----
    Plan to carry on all commerce of the United States by ships of war; advantages of this method.
  - Appendix, Mem. 1p.; -----, -----
    A scheme to pay four hundred millions of American indebtedness by the sale of American timber.
  - Appendix, Mem. 1p.; -----, -----
    Note recording the titles of two books, L'histoire des Finances by M. [François Véron] de Forbonnais, and Tariff Schedules in the Diffrent States of Europe by M. Beaumont.
  - Appendix, 2p.; -----, -----
    Intructions to Postmasters of France as to the method of keeping their records. Printed broadside.
  - Appendix, 1p.; -----, -----
    List of eighteen American toasts given at a dinner in honor of Major-General Charles Cotesworth Pinckney. Printed Broadside.
  - Appendix, Mem. 3p.; -----, -----
    List of English vessels of war with their guns, captains and crews.
  - Appendix, Mem. 1p.; -----, -----
    List of the names and address of several titled French officers.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, Mem. 1p.; Finck, ------
    Expense account.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, Mem. 1p.; -----, -----
    Bill for expenses incurred in capturing and confining seven sailors.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1p.; -----, -----
    Pictorial plan of an air ship.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1p.; -----, -----
    Water-color drawing of a blunderbuss.
    E. "At Mr. Cassan's at Charleville, to be sent to Mr. Clonitz."
  - to ----- de St. Marc., L. in 3d P. 1p.; -----, -----. Paris
    An order to pay M. [Ferdinand] Grand a certain sum due on a cargo of tobacco from Virginia.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, Printed Mem. 1p.; -----, -----
    Description of an engraving of [Marquis de] la Fayette at Yorktown, dedicated to General Washington, by M. [Noël] Le mire.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, Mem. 2p.; -----, -----
    Directions for using a medicinal powder, guaranteed to cure all wounds, and to prevent gangrene.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, Behr, Baron
    Visiting card.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, Mem. 2p.; Franklin?, William Temple
    Quality of gun barrels purchased for use in America, so poor that it is useless to ship them.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, Mem. S. 1p.; Guevelin, Marguerite
    Bill of expenses.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, Hammet, Mr
  - Appendix, Mem. S. 1p.; Jones, Capt. John Paul
    List of men from St. Malo.
  - Appendix, Lee, Mr
  - Appendix, The Bishop of St. Asaph
  - Appendix, 2p.; Swayne and Clifford iron mongers
    List of articles sold at their warehouse. Printed circular.
  - to William Temple Franklin., A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Vaughan, Benjamin
    Enclosing a letter to be forwarded to America.
  - Appendix, Williams, -----. Limner
    Engraved card.